https://unitingwesley.org.au/privacy

Our commitment to your privacy
Wesley Mission Victoria knows that you care how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate you trusting that we will do so carefully. This page explains how we collect and use information about you.
We respect your right to privacy under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) and Privacy and Data Protection Act 2014 (Vic) and comply with our requirements in respect of the collection, management and disclosure of your personal information.
What is your personal information?
This is any information that can be used to personally identify you. We may collect the following types of personal information from you through our website or otherwise: your name, mailing address, email address, telephone number, date of birth, email address, banking details.
Collection of your personal information
We collect personal information from you in a variety of ways, including when you interact with us electronically or in person; when you access our website; when you complete an application or donation or when we provide our services to you.
When your personal information is collected, we will take reasonable steps to ensure you are aware that we have collected this information about you. If you do not provide us with the information we request, we may not be able to fulfil the applicable purpose of collection, such as to supply products or services to you or to process your donation.
We may also collect some information that is not personal information because it does not identify you or anyone else, such as anonymous responses to surveys.
Using your personal information
We collect personal information about you so that we can perform our business activities and functions and to provide you with the best possible quality of service.
When you supply information about yourself for a specific purpose, we will use the information for only that purpose, such as to provide the service or information you have requested, unless certain exceptions apply, such as where your consent has been obtained, where it is reasonably expected to be used for a related purpose or as authorised by law.
We use return email addresses to answer emails we receive. Such addresses are not used for any other purpose and are not shared with outside parties.
You can register with our website if you would like to receive updates on other Wesley Mission Victoria products and services. Information you submit on our website will not be used for this purpose unless you provide your consent.
We do not share your personal information with outside parties except where it is reasonably expected to be disclosed to our business partners and service providers who assist us in the provision of our products and services, or as authorised or required by law.
Our commitment to data security
We take reasonable steps to ensure your personal information is protected from misuse and loss and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. We may hold your information in either electronic or hard copy form (or both). Additionally, sensitive data such as credit card numbers are encrypted using SSL and other industry standard measures, to provide an additional level of security. Personal information is destroyed or de-identified when no longer needed.
Cookies
In some cases, we may also collect your personal information through the use of cookies. When you access our website, we may send a “cookie” (a small summary file containing a unique ID number) to your computer. This enables us to recognise your computer each time you visit our website. We also use cookies to measure traffic patterns, to determine which areas of our website have been visited and to measure transaction patterns in the aggregate. We use this to research our user’s habits so that we can improve the experience for people using our website. Our cookies do not collect personal information. If you do not wish to receive cookies, you can set your browser so that your computer does not accept them.
We may log IP addresses to analyse trends, track site usage and gather broad demographic information. This information is used in an aggregated manner to analyse how people use our site, so that we can improve our service.
Links
This website may contain links to other web sites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another site. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of these linked websites as their privacy policy may differ from ours.
Opting out of communications
We may, from time to time, send you information for marketing purposes. We only do so in accordance with applicable laws or with your prior consent. If you no longer wish to receive information from us, please contact us using the information below asking to be removed from our mailing lists, or use the unsubscribe facilities included in our marketing communications.
Access or update your information
You can access your personal information by contacting us at the details below. We may charge a reasonable administration fee for this access.
If at any time you wish to change personal information that we hold about you because it is inaccurate or out of date, please contact us with your request using the details below.
Complaints about privacy
If you have a complaint about our privacy practices, please contact us using the information below and provide details of the incident so that we can investigate it. We take complaints very seriously and will respond shortly after receiving your written notice. If we fail to respond to your complaint within a reasonable time of receiving it in writing or if you are dissatisfied with the response that you receive, you may have the right to make a complaint to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner or Office of the Victorian Information Commissioner.
Changes to this information
Please be aware that we may change our privacy practices from time to time in the future and any changes will be reflected on this website.
How to contact us
If you have any questions, concerns or comments about privacy, or would like a copy of our privacy charter, you can email privacy@wesley.org.au, telephone 9666 1275 or write to the Privacy Officer, Wesley Mission Victoria at Locked Bag 8, A’Beckett St PO, Melbourne, Victoria 8006.
Support Wesley
Give by Phone
1300 493 753
Send a Cheque
Wesley Mission Victoria Reply Paid 85995 A’Beckett Street VIC 8006
Other ways to Donate
Give hope with a gift in your Will
Stay Involved,
Join our mailing list
Join our mailing list
Phone Enquiries
(03) 9662 2355
Email Enquiries
admin@wesley.org.au
Mailing Address
Locked Bag 8
Staff Login
Wesley Mission Victoria acknowledges the Traditional Owners in each of the communities where we work. We pay our respects to their Elders, past and present.
Organisation Member
Supported by
Thank you
Share
Spread the word
I’ve just made a donation to Wesley Mission Victoria/@WesleyVic! You can change lives like me and make a donation too.
Stay Involved,
Join our mailing list
Join our mailing list
Thank you!
